<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2023-07-05T16:09:41-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Emerson Maddock</title><subtitle>My slice of the internet :) Passonate about geopolitics, economics, tech, and freedom. My journey learning the open-source world!</subtitle><author><name>EmersonMaddock</name></author><entry><title type="html">Creating This Site!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/webdev/2023/07/04/Creating-This-Site!/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating This Site!" /><published>2023-07-04T09:04:58-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-04T09:04:58-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/webdev/2023/07/04/Creating-This-Site!</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/webdev/2023/07/04/Creating-This-Site!/">&lt;p&gt;I made this site for fun as a test to myself. I have learned the jekyll interface from scratch and used it to generate the static pages you are viewing. Using jekyll and hosting through GitHub Pages have both been pretty intuitive, here are the steps I took if you want to do it yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Downloaded Jekyll following &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Followed Quickstart and launched localhost starting website&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Examined interface to understand how to use it – Notice the intuitive use of markdown and file structure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up Visual Studio Code and uploaded the Quickstart to Github&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pages/getting-started-with-github-pages/creating-a-github-pages-site&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Found a theme I liked – &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/daviddarnes/alembic/&quot;&gt;alembic&lt;/a&gt; – and followed their extended interface&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch and Continued Working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for the basics of building a similar website. Also see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>EmersonMaddock</name></author><category term="webdev" /><summary type="html">I made this site for fun as a test to myself. I have learned the jekyll interface from scratch and used it to generate the static pages you are viewing. Using jekyll and hosting through GitHub Pages have both been pretty intuitive, here are the steps I took if you want to do it yourself: Downloaded Jekyll following docs Followed Quickstart and launched localhost starting website Examined interface to understand how to use it – Notice the intuitive use of markdown and file structure Set up Visual Studio Code and uploaded the Quickstart to Github Set up GitHub Pages Found a theme I liked – alembic – and followed their extended interface Launch and Continued Working Check out the Jekyll docs for the basics of building a similar website. Also see Jekyll’s GitHub repo.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>